<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on nightdrops</title>
    <link>https://nightdrops.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on nightdrops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:41:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nightdrops.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes about moving to a remote work position</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2017/notes-about-moving-to-a-remote-work-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2017/notes-about-moving-to-a-remote-work-position/</guid>
      <description>I have moved from a big openspace lots of people office to a remote position for a non-italian company last December.
Furthermore my experience of remote working so far was of a &amp;lsquo;partially&amp;rsquo; remote team, where everyone was sitting around the same table, and having coffees and lunch together and one or two perople were on a distant city - a situation where remote working makes you the &amp;lsquo;foreign&amp;rsquo; element who don&amp;rsquo;t get the jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutation Observer polyfill</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2015/mutation-observer-polyfill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 23:54:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2015/mutation-observer-polyfill/</guid>
      <description>I often use Mutation Observers in my projects. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small polyfill to replace some of the functionalities on the older browsers.
Feel free to contribute! ;-)
{% gist kajyr/c806965e5781b754d8e9 %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing laravel auth and auth-token</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2014/managing-laravel-auth-and-auth-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 23:55:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2014/managing-laravel-auth-and-auth-token/</guid>
      <description>When you develop an app in Laravel, sometimes you need to have a webapp and her native counterpart. To manage the authentication on the API side, there&amp;rsquo;s this lovely package that is tappleby\laravel-auth-token. One of the les documented features of this package is how to maintain in sync the tokens and the laravel auth.
Why? Because when an api is called with the right token, you want to use Auth::user() and Auth::check(), for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you need your pc fixed</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2014/so-you-need-your-pc-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 08:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2014/so-you-need-your-pc-fixed/</guid>
      <description>One in a while ( I said week ?) a friend of mine phones, mostly the one i did not hear for a long time, just to chat and ask me advice on their fallen hard disk, bricked smartphone or whatelse.
I am glad to thank Giorgio, that has pinned the problem and made a website around it: shouldiaskmytechfriendtofixmypc
(Yes, there&amp;rsquo;s a reference to dwsntletsieb ).
Thanks Giorgio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let ghost be</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2014/let-ghost-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:44:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2014/let-ghost-be/</guid>
      <description>After 2 days full of talks at From the Front, I&amp;rsquo;m happily back to work (on saturday, duh).
There were lots of interesting talks and some ideas that needs to be metabolized - not an easy &amp;lsquo;show your code&amp;rsquo; conference for sure! :-)
On a lighter side, what I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist to do after a couple of beers with friends, was updating my blog from wordpress to ghost.
Why?
Because it&amp;rsquo;s minimal, because I love editing posts in Markdown and I find that WYSIWYG editors produce shitty HTML, and because it&amp;rsquo;s on nodejs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About interviews</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2014/about-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:36:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2014/about-interviews/</guid>
      <description>I know it&amp;rsquo;s a widely explored topic, but after a row of bad interviews I would like to spell out what I think it&amp;rsquo;s the baseline to a decent job interview.
A little premise I work in the interface development department of a big company, and I interview web designers, interface developers, frontend developers and sometimes assist my co-workers in other web related interviews
The first thing: character The first and most important questions (IMHO) I ask are open questions about what the candidate thinks about some technology (or anything, really).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compass: from zero to production in 20 minutes</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2013/compass-from-zero-to-production-in-20-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 01:20:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2013/compass-from-zero-to-production-in-20-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we decided it was time to write better css and optimize a little, and we did choose &lt;a title=&#34;compass-style&#34; href=&#34;http://compass-style.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;compass&lt;/a&gt; and the scss syntax as the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project i&amp;rsquo;m workin on is organized with a very big css/ folder with a css for every page, a couple css for the common classes and some css files with fixes for certains nations (I&amp;rsquo;m speaking of Russia, China and Japan, where we have different fonts and all the spacing changes); it is also deployed with continuous integration on several test environments and the production cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past we did try a conversion to less, but it was unsuccessful, mainly because the less syntax is not compatible with css so we needed to restyle every page (a lot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We planned a lot on how to introduce the scss files and after several tries we noted that:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 14px;&#34;&gt;it was unnecessary to rewrite a single line of css: the scss syntax is superset of css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;we did not need to convert scss file live and cache them - at the beginning we could source control both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Once all the interface developers were the loop and motivated (pretty easy ;-), we decided to migrate in steps, to make the transition easy:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy the css folder to a new &amp;lsquo;sass&amp;rsquo; folder and rename (batch rename) all the files to .scss&lt;/strong&gt;, commit and celebrate. This is the core action to introduce sass.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modify the continuous integration script to recompile all the css during the build/deploy task&lt;/strong&gt;: this way we could remove the css file from versioning and avoid unnecessary merges&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modify the above script to deploy the generated sprites: &lt;/strong&gt;we keep them on different servers and we decided it was not a vital step, so we separated from the second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The big point is that between step 1 and 2 we let several days pass by. This way all the developers could taste the scss sweetness and bring their sub-projects up to speed. We don&amp;rsquo;t like big changes   :-). Beside that, the first step is really the core of setting up scss, and it only takes a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ffmpeg not found after brew installing</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2013/ffmpeg-not-found-after-brew-installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 03:18:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2013/ffmpeg-not-found-after-brew-installing/</guid>
      <description>After installing ffmpeg on my Mac OS X with brew (with the command)
brew install ffmpeg --use-clang
I could not reach ffmpeg from the command line. For some reason the installer forgot to link the bin file. Simply solved with
`ln /usr/local/Cellar/ffmpeg/1.0/bin/ffmpeg /usr/local/bin/
Posted just in case this happens to someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainy mood</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2013/rainy-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 02:57:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2013/rainy-mood/</guid>
      <description>This site it&amp;rsquo;s incredible.
image courtesy of Logophile Basically it has rain-in-the-forest recording that loops. You have to listen to it with (a good pair of) headphones, and it will make you think that you are in a forest, during a storm (except you don&amp;rsquo;t get wet).
I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered it a years ago, more or less, and I am always keeping it open when I work. It is a great way to isolate you acoustically and concentrate, without the distraction that random music with lyrics brings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: Hide or show input passwords</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2012/tutorial-hide-or-show-input-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 21:43:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2012/tutorial-hide-or-show-input-passwords/</guid>
      <description>When typing a password, on desktop devices,the dots that are covering typed characters are useful, because we can assume that somebody might walk behind our desk and look at the password we are typing.
Password: On mobile devices, it&amp;rsquo;s harder to look - we hold the device in hand - and it&amp;rsquo;s easier to make a mistake.
When the password is a key step in your business (to buy something, for example), you don&amp;rsquo;t want users to go away because they are tired of rewriting a miswritten password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity: phantomjs</title>
      <link>https://nightdrops.com/2012/serendipity-phantomjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:37:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nightdrops.com/2012/serendipity-phantomjs/</guid>
      <description>So while browsing pointless the intertubes, this post came to my attention, and I started reading about phantomjs. I had already seen this project but never tried it. Now I&amp;rsquo;m officially curious.
This is the code to make a screenshot of a full web page:
{% highlight javascript %} var page = require(&amp;lsquo;webpage&amp;rsquo;).create(); page.open(&amp;lsquo;http://google.com&#39;, function () { page.render(&amp;lsquo;google.png&amp;rsquo;); phantom.exit(); }); {% endhighlight %}
I&amp;rsquo;m totally hooked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>